gemrockauctions.com 2016-03-31

# Help: Privacy Policy

## Gem Rock Auctions IS COMMITTED TO YOUR PRIVACY

Your privacy on the internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Gem Rock Auctions, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

## INFORMATION Gem Rock Auctions GATHERS AND TRACKS

Gem Rock Auctions gathers two types of information about users: 

  * Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to register for our services, receive our electronic newsletter, to participate in our message boards or forums, by using the common features of our site, and from participation in polls and surveys. 
  * Information Gem Rock Auctions gathers through monitoring the site visitors. This information does not personally identify a visitor, only providing a general overview of the visitor, such as which city and country they are located in, what website referred them to Opal Auctions, and the duration of their visit. This data is automatically correlated to provide an overview and does not contain any sensitive information. For more information, please refer to our tracking software makers privacy policy, [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/privacy.html). 

**1\. Registration Details**

In order to register on Gem Rock Auctions, you are required to provide personal information including your name, phone number, email address and postal address. This information is essential because our auction site is dependant on your details to post any won items to you in the mail. Your personal information is used exclusively for the above stated purpose, and is not shared with any 3rd parties unless required by law. 

**2\. Electronic newsletters policy**

We offer a free electronic newsletter to members. Gem Rock Auctions gathers the email addresses of users by retrieving them from our member database. Members may remove themselves from this mailing list at any time by following the link provided in every newsletter that points members to the unsubscription page. Alternatively, click here to unsubscribe from the Gem Rock Auctions newsletter. Members will be automatically subscribed upon registration. 

**3\. Forum policy**

Members of the Gem Rock Auctions Forum must register separately for this service (free of charge) in order to post messages, although they needn’t register to browse through the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address. These details are subject to the same policy as Gem Rock Auctions members, in that they **will NOT be shared with 3rd parties**. 

**4\. “E-mail this to a friend” policy**

Our site users can choose to electronically forward details of a selected auction to someone else by clicking “e-mail this to a friend”. The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. No record is made of this transmission, and the email addresses provided will not be used for any other purpose. 

**5\. Polling**

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user.Gem Rock Auctions may use a system to “tag” users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 

**6\. Surveys**

Gem Rock Auctions may occasionally conduct user surveys to better understand our visitors. Gem Rock Auctions may use a system to “tag” users after they have complete a survey, so they can submit the same survey only once. We never share any information about specific individuals with any third party. 

**7\. Children**

Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

**8\. Cookies**

We may place a text file called a “cookie” in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain personal information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provide A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites.Gem Rock Auctions uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above), and perform basic functions related to logging in and out. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you’ve set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you may experience some abnormal behaviour while interacting with non-essential site features. Cookies do not relate to bidding and will have no adverse effect on buying or selling whether they are enabled or disabled in your browser. 

## USE OF INFORMATION

Gem Rock Auctions uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalised elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. **Your personal information is required to post items to you in the mail, and is not used for any other purpose**. Your postal address and actual name is made available to sellers on Gem Rock Auctions so that they may deliver items to you. **Your information is not made available to sellers unless you have bidded and won an item that they have listed.**

We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule, and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Gem Rock Auctions never shares or sells newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

We use tracking information to determine ways to better enrich the user experience. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in the search function as one of many measures to ascertain what interests our users. We do not have any mechanism that matches a submitted search term to the user who entered it. 

Gem Rock Auctions creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. While summaries of this information may be shared when necessary to further promote our site, **NO PERSONAL INFORMATION WILL BE SHARED WITH 3RD PARTY ADVERTISERS, SPONSORS OR PARTNERS.**

## SHARING OF THE INFORMATION

Gem Rock Auctions uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience’s demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. **We will not share information about individual users with any third party** , except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

## SECURITY

Gem Rock Auctions operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers. 

## OPT-OUT POLICY

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 

  * **Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters.**
  * **Opting not to register for the auctions service, or revoke your membership which will minimise the information available to us, and also prevent you accessing members only functions and service areas**

## YOUR CONSENT

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Gem Rock Auctions. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page and notify members in our news section, so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
